

## MUHAMMAD AMIR HAMZAH

Aspiring Data Analyst

+6018-910 3791

amiriium381@gmail.com 

Bukit Katil, Melaka

in www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-amir-hamzah 🔗 amoiiir.github.io

## **ABOUT ME**

A student specializing in Business Intelligence and Analytics, possessing experience in analytical and technical skills within the Information Technology field, seeks an internship placement in data analytics or **information technology** to enhance future growth in the IT domain.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor in Information Technology** International Islamic University Malaysia 2020 - 2024 (expected)

Foundation in Information Technology International Islamic University Malaysia 2019 - 2020

Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM) Maktab Rendah Sains Mara 2014 - 2018

CGPA: 3.70 |



CGPA: 3.33



SPM: 5As



## **Analytical Skills**

- Microsoft Office
- Data Visualizations
- Tableau
- Data Cleaning
- SQL
- Statistics and Analytics

#### Other Skills & IT Languages

- Flutter & Firebase
- · Adobe Photoshop
- Web Development
- R & Python
- Data Warehousing
- Project Management

#### Languages

 English Bahasa Malaysia Arabic

## **PROJECTS**

#### SwitchAR: AR Virtual Switch Control For IoT-based Smart Home Automation 2023

- · A partnered Final Year Project that aims to help the elderly to become more independent when interacting with home appliances.
- Proposed solution by developing a mobile application using Flutter and Unity application that implements the concepts of Internet of Things (IoT) and Augmented Reality (AR).

#### Tools used:









**Blynk** 

**Arduino IDE** 

**Vuforia** 

## **Crime Dataset Analysis 2023**

- Coordinated a group of four people to investigate the crime rate in Malaysia from the year 2015 until 2020.
- Provided insights on the trends of crime rate through visualizations and interactive dashboards.
- · Datasets analyzed were obtained from Malaysian Open Data Portal at https://data.gov.my.

#### Tools used:





**Tableau** 

**Microsoft** Excel

#### Covid-19 Data Cleaning 2023

- · Self-learned project data cleaning basics using SQL Server through a YouTube course.
- Utilized data sourced from https://ourworldindata.org/covid-deaths to clean and transform raw data into a structured format suitable for visualization purposes.

#### Tools used:



Standard Query Language



SQL Server **Management Studio** 

## **WORKING EXPERIENCE**



MELAKA • MALAYSIA

## **Housekeeping Department - Part Time**

August 2022 - October 2022

Bayou Lagoon Park Resort

- Managed inventory and calculated essential supplies, such as linens and bedsheet to ensure operational efficiency.
- Provided engaging guest entertainment for a two month period, enhancing visitors experiences through personalized and lively interactions.

## **LEADERSHIP**

#### **KPMG Student Ambassadors 2023**

January 2023 - December 2023



- Strategized engaging physical and virtual events to facilitate connections between IIUM students and KPMG mentors.
- Executed workshops aimed at enhancing students' job market competitiveness.
- Achievement: managed to gather 30 to 40 students to a physical event in IIUM.



September 2022 - January 2023



- Volunteered to be part of committee member of ICT Student Society 2022/2023, contributing to various student activities.
- Managed the arrangement of the venue and equipment for upcoming events, ensuring a seamless and successful execution.

## **AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENT**

## **Malaysia Data Innovation Talent 2023**

- Participant won top 50 among 120 groups in national level.
- Analyzed datasets from openDOSM related to housing affordability across income groups and provide solutions through dashboards and analytics.

## Final Year Project - 1st Place in System Development Category

 Awarded 1st place in the System Development category for the Final Year Project from department of KICT.

#### **Dean's List Award**

- Semester 1 and 2, 2020/2021
- Semester 1 and 2, 2022/2023
- Semester 1 and 2, 2023/2024

# Program Pemantapan Bahasa, Sesi 2022/2023

- Competed in a university-level challenge, presenting innovative traffic improvement solutions for the IIUM.
- Secured a fifth-place ranking out of nine participants.

## **REFERENCES**

#### Dr. Zainatul Shima Abdullah

IAP Coordinator IIUM

Department of Information System,

Kulliyyah of Information & Communication Technology, International Islamic University Malaysia,

shima@iium.edu.my

#### Dr. Madihah Bt. S. Abd. Aziz

Deputy Director, Centre for Professional Development, Department of Information System,

Kulliyyah of Information & Communication Technology, International Islamic University Malaysia, madihahs@iium.edu.my